Guide to the GI Bill Oral Histories
GI Bill Oral Histories
2003-2004
2003 2004
North Carolina State University Libraries
MC 00019
This collection of oral histories contains audiocassette tapes, 2003-2004, of interviews with GI Bill veterans who attended North Carolina State College (later North Carolina State University). The interviewees were twelve servicemen and -women who were in the armed forces during World War II, the Korean War and Vietnam War eras, and later. The interviews cover the subjects' military service, educational experiences, GI Bill benefits, and professional careers. Also included for some interviews are tape logs--typed partial transcripts with abridged or paraphrased questions and answers, along with tape counter numbers. Interviews were conducted by Anna Dahlstein, NCSU Libraries Fellow, and Robert Serow, Professor, Education Research, College of Education, North Carolina State University.
The interviews in the GI Bill Oral Histories were conducted in conjunction with Transforming Society: The GI Bill Experience at NC State, an exhibit prepared by the North Carolina State University Libraries to celebrate the sixtieth anniversary of the original GI Bill of Rights, the Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944, and to honor those whom the legislation and its subsequent reenactments enabled to attend the university.
1 linear feet
2 cassette boxes and 1 archival half box
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Use of audiotapes may require production of copies for use.
This collection was created by the NCSU Libraries on 2006 April 25 (Accession no. 2006-0010).
This collection is arranged alphabetically by interview subject.
The interviews in the GI Bill Oral Histories were conducted in 2003 and 2004 in conjunction with an exhibit prepared by the North Carolina State University Libraries to celebrate the sixtieth anniversary of the original GI Bill of Rights, the Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944, and to honor those whom the legislation and its subsequent reenactments enabled to attend North Carolina State. Titled Transforming Society: The GI Bill Experience at NC State, the exhibit was on display at the university's D. H. Hill Library in 2004. The oral histories were conducted by NCSU Libraries Fellow Anna Dahlstein and Robert C. Serow, professor of education at NC State.
NCSU Libraries exhibit: Transforming Society: The GI Bill Experience at NC State
The GI Bill Oral Histories contains audiocassette tapes, 2003-2004, of interviews of GI Bill veterans who attended North Carolina State College (later North Carolina State University). The interviewees were twelve servicemen and -women who were in the armed forces during World War II, the Korean War and Vietnam War eras, and later. The interviews cover the subjects' military service, educational experiences, GI Bill benefits, and professional careers. Also included for some interviews are tape logs--typed partial transcripts with abridged or paraphrased questions and answers, along with tape counter numbers. Interviews were conducted by Anna Dahlstein, NCSU Libraries Fellow, and Robert Serow, Professor, Education Research, College of Education, North Carolina State University.
North Carolina State University--Students--History; North Carolina State University Libraries; Dahlstein Anna; United States Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944; Serow Robert C. 1947-; Audiotapes; Oral histories (document genres); War and society; Education United States Veterans
- Harry Allen, Jr., 2003; 2003 2003
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.01 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 2, Audiocassette 19.01 User)
  - Tape Log (Halfbox 1, Folder 1)
- Leigh H. Hammond, 2004; 2004 2004
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.02 Master)
- Sion H. Harrington III, 2003; 2003 2003
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.03 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 2, Audiocassette 19.03 User)
  - Tape Log (Halfbox 1, Folder 1)
- Charles J. McCann, 2003; 2003 2003
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.04 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 2, Audiocassette 19.04 User)
  - Tape Log (Halfbox 1, Folder 1)
- Kathryn Maitrejean, 2004; 2004 2004
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.05 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 2, Audiocassette 19.05 User)
- Theodore J. Meyer, 2003; 2003 2003
  - Master Tape (1 of 2) (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.06/1 of 2 Master)
  - Master Tape (2 of 2) (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.06/2 of 2 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 2, Audiocassette 19.06 User)
  - Tape Log (Halfbox 1, Folder 1)
- Bobby D. Moore, 2004; 2004 2004
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.07 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.07 User)
- Donald E. Moreland, 2003; 2003 2003
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.08 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 2, Audiocassette 19.08 User)
  - Tape Log (Halfbox 1, Folder 1)
- Richard E. Peterson, 2003; 2003 2003
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.09 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 2, Audiocassette 19.09 User)
  - Tape Log (Halfbox 1, Folder 1)
- Jules C. Rivera, 2004; 2004 2004
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.10 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.10 User)
  - Tape Log (Halfbox 1, Folder 1)
- Bob G. Roberts, 2004; 2004 2004
  - Master Tape (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.11 Master)
  - User Copy (Cassettebox 2, Audiocassette 19.11 User)
- Bruce J. and Barbara Zobel, 2003; 2003 2003
  - Master Copy (Cassettebox 1, Audiocassette 19.12 Master)
  - Tape Log (Halfbox 1, Folder 1)